Alessandro Roic

Front End Developer with 3 years of experience building modular and responsive website designs. Capable of managing projects independently, able to plan and systematically organize my work. Focused on details, keeping up with deadlines, and pre-established budgets. Always eager to improve my skills with hands-on experience and interested in learning new technologies. Authorized to work for any Canadian employer for six months without an LMIA.

Work Experience

Front End Developer / Accenture

- February 2021 to Present
- ® Rome, Italy
- Led a team of 4 software developers for a project, using knowledge of accessibility standards (WCAG 2) to achieve an outstanding score of 93/100 on Google Lighthouse.
- Developed and maintained 10+ repositories for a multinational banking website, using **React 17** to build modular and reactive micro front ends.
- Collaborated with a scrum team of 20 engineers and designers, employing excellent verbal and written communication skills to build positive working relationships.
- Self-managed, implemented, and deployed a data management app with **Angular 13** for a bank's internal tool, providing operators with a simple way to view client data.
- Tested components and pages using Karma & Jasmine for an online banking website, resulting in 100% code coverage.

Full Stack Developer / Jpanik

- October 2019 to February 2021
- Rome, Italy
- Implemented pages and services for a hospital management web app, handling heavy workloads during the pandemic by prioritizing and organizing tasks, resulting in zero service disruption.
- Integrated an interactive graph using the library **Chart.js**, providing a helpful visual reference to healthcare professionals.
- Developed **RESTful APIs** using **Spring Boot** to create scalable and performant services.
- Upgraded AngularJS components to Angular 8, improving performance and readability, and cutting development time by 25%.

Education & Certifications

Bachelor of Computer Science / Sapienza University of Rome

September 2016 to April 2020

Study Abroad / Rijksuniversiteit Groningen

☐ September 2017 to March 2018

© Groningen, Netherlands

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

□ 05 August 2022 to 05 August 2022

Skills

- Programming: Javascript (ES6+), Typescript, HTML, CSS / Sass, Java, SQL, REST API, XML, JSON.
- Libraries & Frameworks: Node.js, Angular, React, Vue, Redux, Bootstrap, Jest, Karma, Storybook, NgRx, RxJs, Anime.js, Styled Components, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MongoDB.
- Tools & Platforms: Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Gitlab, Github, Npm, Figma.
- Languages: English (professional proficiency IELTS 7.5), Italian (Native).

Projects

- Personal Website: portfolio built with Vue 3 and deployed to Github pages.
- <u>CamoNotifications</u>: React 18 library for showing notifications that adapts to your page.
- <u>E-Quality</u>: video game aimed at raising gender-equality awareness, developed using **Unity** in collaboration with the Italian Regional Council for Equal Opportunities.
- AirborneAssault: action video game built with libGDX for the university Java course.